<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HeartBit</string>
    <string name="ble_not_supported">Sorry, Bluetooth Low Energy is not supported on this device.</string>
    <string name="intro_title">Welcome to HeartBit!</string>
    <string name="intro_text">This application will coach you through a simple breathing routine. During this time, it will collect information about your heart rate from a Polar heart rate monitor. This data will be stored on our secure server for research purposes.\n\nBy using this app, you are helping us research the effect of heart rate variability (HRV) on overall health and wellness. Thank you for participating!\n\nWhen you are ready to begin, enter your first name in the field below and click \"Start\" to begin using the app.
    </string>
    <string name="instructions_title">Instructions</string>
    <string name="instructions">To use this app, just follow these steps:\n\n1. Put on your Polar heart rate monitor and wait until the word \"Connected\" appears at the top of the screen.\n\n2. Press \"Start\" to begin your breathing session. Breathe in and out as instructed by the app. Please do not close the application or engage in other activities during the breathing session. Match your breathing rate as closely as possible to the progress of the blue circle on the screen. The green bar will be full when the recommended 3-minute duration has been reached.\n\n3. After 3 minutes, you can stop the breathing session at any time by pressing the \"Stop\" button. You can stop the session before 3 minutes if you need to, but this will provide less useful data for our research.\n\n4. Wait until the app says that your data has been saved before closing the app.\n\nYou can review these instructions at any time by clicking the question mark on the main screen.</string>
    <string name="summary_instructions">Breathe in through your nose while the word “inhale” is shown, and breathe out through pursed lips while the word \"exhale\" is shown.\n\nIf you become lightheaded, stop the session and try again later.</string>
    <string name="start_btn_text">Start</string>
    <string name="stop_btn_text">Stop</string>
    <string name="early_termination_warning_title">Are you sure?</string>
    <string name="early_termination_warning">The current breathing session is less the recommended time. If you stop now, we won\'t get the high-quality data we need for our research.\n\nAre you sure you want to stop the session now?
    </string>
    <string name="stop_session_text">Stop Session</string>
    <string name="continue_session_text">Continue Session</string>
    <string name="connection_status_label">Monitor Status:</string>
    <string name="connection_status_ok">Connected</string>
    <string name="connection_status_none">Disconnected</string>
    <string name="connection_status_connecting">Connecting</string>
    <string name="connection_status_waiting">Waiting for Data</string>
    <string name="remaining_time_label">Time Remaining</string>
    <string name="data_saved_message">Your data has been uploaded successfully.\nYou may now exit the app, or begin another breathing session.</string>
    <string name="permission_request_explanation_title">Access Required</string>
    <string name="permission_request_explanation">In a moment, we will ask you to grant one or more permissions to HeartBit. These permissions are required for the app to function.</string>
    <string name="permission_denied_title">Unable To Continue</string>
    <string name="permission_denied_message">Since location access has not been granted, this app will not be able to scan for the heart rate monitor.</string>
    <string name="monitor_not_found_title">Unable To Connect</string>
    <string name="monitor_not_found_message">The heart rate monitor could not be found. Please ensure it is being worn correctly before continuing.</string>
    <string name="name_label_text">Your Name:</string>
    <string name="name_field_error">Please enter your first name.</string>
    <string name="main_activity_title">Breathing Session</string>
    <string name="breathe_in">inhale</string>
    <string name="breathe_out">exhale</string>
    <string name="help_link_text">\?</string>
    <string name="researcher_name">Dr. B</string>
    <string name="researcher_mode_unlock_message">Researcher mode unlocked!</string>
    <string name="activity_picker_title">Select Activity</string>
    <string name="participant_activity_name">Participant Activity</string>
    <string name="researcher_activity_name">Researcher Activity</string>
    <string name="timeout_warning">Make sure Polar is secure</string>
    <string name="settings_title">Breathing Rate Settings</string>
    <string name="in_out_pair_label">Inhale Duration = Exhale Duration</string>
    <string name="in_title">Inhale Duration</string>
    <string name="out_title">Exhale Duration</string>
    <string name="both_title">Inhale/Exhale Duration</string>
    <string name="min_label">min</string>
    <string name="sec_label">sec</string>
    <string name="ms_label">ms</string>
    <string name="session_length_title">Session Duration</string>
    <string name="part_settings_enable_label">Participant settings enabled</string>
    <string name="save_btn_text">Save</string>
    <string name="copy_btn_text">Copy to Participant Settings</string>
    <string name="copy_success_msg">Settings copied</string>
    <string name="password_prompt_title">Researcher Mode</string>
    <string name="password_prompt_message">If you are a researcher, please enter the Researcher Password below. Otherwise, please press "cancel" to return to the breathing exercise screen.</string>
    <string name="cancel_btn_text">Cancel</string>
    <string name="enter_btn_text">Enter</string>
    <string name="top_secret_password">hrv4science</string>
    <string name="wrong_password_message">Nice try!</string>
</resources>
